All right, we'll call the regular meeting of the City Council for Tuesday, May, our July 21st and we'll call the order in the public input around the schedule of the passes by three consent agenda items forward through eight.
Make questions on the question to the group.
Before we item eight, there weren't any changes from last year's words there.
I couldn't let there one couple of minor changes.
For instance, we report from your clause.
We now include the pain dynamics.
There's a reason to justify non-compliance.
Okay.
And we incorporated the name of use, advertising, all the stuff.
That's sort of that.
Can't remember any others.
I'll make a question to the group, consent agenda.
Okay.
Work it.
All right.
Lewis.
Hi.
Weston.
Our Davis.
Hi.
Parker.
My nine, nine.
Mayor's nomination of Councilmember.
The serve is Mayor Proctin.
And I will nominate Councilman David Davis.
So, I have to.
Can you say that?
I'll second it.
Work it.
All right.
Lewis.
Weston.
Davis.
All right.
You don't have to.
Hey, line on.
10 minutes from June 17, June 23rd.
And June 30th.
Motion to approve those.
Seven.
Second.
Work it.
Say this.
All right.
Weston, Lewis, I, Parker.
I have a thing.
I'm 11, for turn order of police, FOP logical.
21, fiscal year 2020, and 2021 contract, Ms. Kim Warner.
This evening, we're asking you to approve the
return order of police contract, collective bargaining agreement
with the city of Miami.
And there are three changes from the previous year's contract,
so I'll just briefly mention those.
One of them is, our previous year contract actually was a two-year
contract, and what we're recommending this year is a one-year contract.
This new proposed CDA includes a 2% increase in the salary ranges,
and then there's just a small change in Article 23, which is
grooming.
We've taken out the word, go-t, and added facial hair.
That was a pretty small request.
The chief was fine when with how the guys, I'm the ladies,
they're facial hair, I mean, I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
With a situation that had a pinky, would have to be bidding as a hand,
where that's why it's having to be traded.
Right.
So we added that language, even though that doesn't have to be very often.
We added that language, so we're asking you to approve that,
that's fine.
Sorry, been long day.
So we have a motion to approve, contract?
I don't approve.
But if you think you can do make that motion, you can add a list.
I'd question, are Davis, or get Parker?
Hi.
Fine, I'm 12 of the word, a financing, a new pepper truck and a finger truck.
I'm just interested to do, huh?
Me?
So here, on behalf of the part of part of it, to present to you the results from our request
for proposals for financing of the pump or truck and the tank or truck, which counsel previously
for purchase, provided a table in where you are, in the VA, in the VA, which you have in your
packets, where you can see a general rate comparison, but also in your packet, a more detailed
spreadsheet of the cost comparison and the actual documents provided to us in this
part.
So with that said, we are recommending US Bank as a financing for this acquisition.
You can see that in 7 year, at 7.
in your world, or at least agreement, they are two and four percent, which is really good,
they're really good for that, and we looked at more than just the interest rate though,
we looked at associated fees, pre-payment penalties, the opportunity to keep us within
budget, and of course just the overall repayment.
The U.S. bank has proposed, provides us in scenario where our budgeted payment is more
than our required payment, to savings to the city of about 27 and almost 28 dollar dollars,
and that allows us to, it gives us flexibility, first of all, but it also allows us to pay
off that truck earlier, any time, probably, after five years, we can probably pay it off.
So we solicited, if you're wondering, solicited, nine financing agencies, all of our local banks
had enough opportunity, and we reached out to some others who asked to be on our vendor list.
We have four responses in addition to what PNC was offering us in their sales, we were buying
the truck from peers, peers had their own financing agency.
Unfortunately, they have a really high penalties on paying it off early, at any time, 3%
of your balance, so when you are at the mid-mid-mid-mid-mid.
So, did you have any questions?
Have any answer?
I had a question on the, one of them showed, been up again here in two months, and the other one showed
seven months.
Right.
Initially, both trucks that we wanted were on dealership lots, but there has just been a run.
After manufacturing and started kicking back up after the COVID closed downs, the trucks were
really fast off the lots.
So before we get all of our things finalized, one truck, the tanker, was no longer available
in a while.
So, they say that in seven months they will have it to us.
The other one is two months, and that's giving us a lot of great, something that's probably
the rest of the 30 days, because it is on a lot and it will come right to us.
And just also to that payment amount.
It's in your packet, but it's a combined payment for both the trucks.
We've kept them separate, and separate lease agreements in case we ever wanted to.
So one or whatever, 7,847 dollars and 17 cents a month, or annual payment of 94,166.04, and that's savings.
27,833,96, because we currently have budgeted 120,000 annually for the cost of purchasing drugs.
Then the truck were sending back.
They picked it up today.
And what was the lease on that one?
The remainder of the lease was 82,000, 87,000.
What was it monthly?
You know?
$9,000, I think, a month for both of them.
Okay.
$3,12,000 a year.
So we're actually releasing two more and saving a little bit of them.
It was in it.
So they're basically buying a truck back from us, because they're releasing this from the obligation to pay the remainder of the balance on that truck.
With them having picked up that truck today, how does that leave you guys if we're possibly six months out?
Well, it should be around 30 days, we're expecting.
Okay.
But when this truck was down, we would use our ladder as a main bumper.
And that's what we're going to do until we get the new engine.
Okay.
As we'll just utilize ladder for cold.
Any more questions?
Motion to a brief.
12 second.
Thank you.
Davis.
I think it's Chris Torquett.
Hi.
Lewis.
Western.
Hi.
Parker.
I'm 19.
with what they've done for us and helped us.
We would like to stay with them.
The Gremont's 46,000 leave,
and it would go to the FAA grant portion,
which will be reimbursed.
We had originally budgeted for the whole project.
The whole project is going to be about $675,000.
And originally our city mat was about 50,000.
And because of the way...
They didn't do the CARES Act, they gave so much for airports, and they matched part of the CARES
Funding, they matched the FAA portion of the city's obligation.
So our obligation for the entire project should be about $11,000 now.
I'm a total project cost of just $100,000.
The first 13 is just approving the Garver Professional Service Agreement to oversee the project.
So, most of the approved 13, and you're going to go on the 14-15, or do we approve very well?
And then, first on that is allow the city manager to sign off on any further paperwork with the item, with the agreement.
Any questions for me?
I don't know any of those.
So, most of the approved.
It's approved.
And then the heck of a deal.
Yeah.
That's sweet.
What was the key?
The key.
I'm sorry.
Louis Davis.
All right.
So, now we're going to go to the 14.
I'm going to approve it.
Okay.
Yeah.
I think we need to go separately.
It'll be best.
Thank you.
All right.
I'll say.
I'll be.
What?
Okay.
I'll be.
All right.
And, emotion on 15.
And 15 just allow us to be Congresswoman of the Grand Prix of Work to to.
Louis.
It's like a...
Louis, Constant on Davis.
All right.
Parker.
Thank you.
16 in the other new business.
17 staff reports, 18 mayor and council community announcements in terms of the
manager's communication.
I have three things.
Eight men was a look like a really good success and there was lots of people
pictures.
I mean, talking to Amanda and different things.
It seemed like it brought a lot of people into the city so that was a really good deal.
And then second, Main Street has started.
So, I know they're removing concrete today, so that's good.
We'll be excited about that and then the last one is thank you to Buffalo Run for allowing us to
partner with us on the fireworks that we had on the 4th of July, did not bring that to the last meeting,
and so I made enough to bring it up today, so thank you again for allowing us to do that.
It was really good for our work, sure.
You know, I think I saw Dino's President, Professor Stafford, John Man, please, what's the
eight minutes we have to?
Yeah.
However, I'm just going to actually ask if it's, I don't have this right time, the Fairgrounds,
where are the question about the Fairgrounds?
So they are digging at, which given can it address it more, but they're digging up the dirt
to put rock in there, so the Carnival could during the Fair, the Carnival can actually be inside.
Instead of across the street is where there's all the flooding, the parking, the parking is all.
Okay.
The ground's just wet all the time, so what we did is, we got the state and all the buildings
that they did on the highway, between Boatack and there, we done that out, you know, close
out our Smith side, our regulations side, and we're filling that up the buildings.
One of the biggest concerns the Fairbord had, but it's with Carnival across the street, one
of the kids crossing that floor, but they got nobody into the exhibition building, and the
vendors were really hard, so it kind of came to us and said, does there any way you're
doing anything to give us on the inside of the area, it's so wet for so many years, so to help
where you'll lie on that fairbord, and any of it goes on that, that just created parking on the
end field, and it didn't cost to see if they could okay.
Do you need anything else?
Any other questions?
For the time.
So the motion to adjourn.
So.
Let's go.
Work it.
All right.
Davis.